- [thudding]
- [footsteps running]
[AGOTT] It's mating season
for the scalewolves.
To prevent injury
to their coming offspring,
they use sharp bodily impact
to shed their plaitscale fur.
Were they to forgo mating,
they wouldn't have
to weaken themselves.
I sincerely believed
that there was nothing
I could learn from her.
That Outsiders
didn't belong here,
that they had nothing of value
to offer the world of magic.
But...
if she can learn
how all of it works,
just as the rest of us do,
how is she different?
[♪ opening theme song playing]
[pen scribbling]
[Coco gasps excitedly]
All right! I did it!
You most certainly did!
You've developed
a reliable talent
for drawing your spells.
Well done.
[COCO] I'm so happy!
But still...
There aren't many spells
I'm fully confident
in my ability to draw.
I keep falling back on the seals
I'm more comfortable with.
- [Coco sighs]
- [brushbuddy squeaks]
[QIFREY] If you ask me,
those particular spells...
the ones you can complete
easily and consistently,
are, in fact, your specialty.
[Coco gasps softly]
♪
I have a... specialty?
[QIFREY] Hm.
Take a look.
See the common thread?
All of these spells
include straight lines.
Look at the difference
in confidence between
your curved lines
and your straight ones.
Think back to the day
we first met.
You were drawing straight lines
then as well.
Every witch
has their own specialty.
Identifying yours
will give you confidence,
when you need
to believe in yourself.
If you're uneasy,
say it aloud.
Let your ears hear the words.
My specialty is straight lines.
They're what I can always draw.
It's true, isn't it?
Straight lines are my specialty!
From now on,
I'll focus on straight lines!
Now onward on a straight line
to success I go!
Now, now, not so fast,
young lady!
[COCO] Huh?
Mastery of your specialty spells
will come naturally.
The spells you'd do well
to practice,
are the very ones
that give you the most trouble.
In so doing, you may even
find new specialties.
[Coco gasps softly]
[QIFREY] Ready to start?
[Coco chuckles nervously]
Uh-huh.
[paper rustles]
[COCO] Incredible.
Casting Seals are more
and more impressive to me.
[Coco gasps softly]
With everything
I've learned about them,
the specifics
of exactly how they work...
I can appreciate how hard
they must have been to design.
[Coco exclaims]
- Incredible. Truly incredible!
- [QIFREY] Uh?
Incredible magic drawn
by incredible people!
Her vocabulary of praise
- is rather limited.
- [Qifrey chuckles]
[COCO] This all feels
incredibly beyond me.
Want to come look, Richeh?
- [RICHEH] No.
- [brushbuddy squeaks]
I have no interest in looking.
I prefer to draw.
[COCO] Really? Are you sure?
- There's so much to learn!
- [RICHEH] Very sure.
- It's incredible!
- [RICHEH] And stop your swaying.
[Coco sighs]
There is more
to the study of magic
than training your hands,
you know.
- Much more.
- [scribbling]
By turning our focus to
the advanced spells of others,
we witches can
effectively train our eyes to--
[RICHEH] I don't want to!
Richeh, are you hurt?
Let's see.
My dear girl,
you mustn't cast spells
while agitated.
It's dangerous.
[Richeh grunts]
Wait. Richeh, hold on!
[OLRUGGIO] With eyes closed
to the guideposts of learning
and ears plugged to
the words of your teacher,
you've nowhere to go
and no way to get there.
[Qifrey gasps softly]
- [door closes]
- [running footsteps]
[Coco pants] Richeh!
I, um... I'm really sorry.
I didn't...
[COCO] Huh?
Richeh, are you...
in here?
[door closes]
Where could she have gone?
[brushbuddy squeaks]
What's wrong?
Do you know where she is?
[brushbuddy huffs]
[yelps] What are you
doing in there?
[Coco gasps, yelps]
[Coco exhales]
[COCO] Brushbuddy?
What is this place?
[Coco gasps softly]
- [wind blowing]
- Huh?
[Coco gasps]
[gasps]
[exclaims excitedly]
[brushbuddy squeaks]
Don't recall inviting you here.
Oh, sorry.
I followed brushbuddy.
What a beautiful spell this is!
It's like ribbons
made out of crystal!
[chuckles]
[RICHEH] I made it myself.
Haven't named it yet.
You made your very own spell?
Now that really is incredible!
It's beautiful, Richeh!
My eyes are so happy! [laughs]
[RICHEH] Unique perspective
you've got there.
[Coco continues laughing]
I really...
really love this spell.
[Coco laughs]
[Richeh gasps softly]
[RICHEH] You can take one
if you want.
[Coco gasps]
[RICHEH] I have plenty.
What? Really? [chuckles]
Thank you!
I'm honored!
So, uh...
Can I ask something?
Why don't you want
to look at spell books?
Maybe it's because
I still have so much
to learn about magic.
But to me, it's a pleasure.
I adore it!
Imagining who invented
the spells, and for what!
It's one of the best parts
of magic for me.
Not for me.
I don't want to think
about anyone's spells but mine.
I know what would happen
if I looked at those books.
They'd start making me copy
whatever was in them.
I'd have to draw things
I didn't want to.
Spells that aren't my style.
I'd hate that.
Richeh.
It's nothing to do with you.
I just don't need
other people's spells.
Not one bit.
They'd only contaminate mine.
[QIFREY] You know,
Richeh only joined us here
after her apprenticeship
to another witch
came to an untimely end.
That stubbornness of hers
is a shield she hides behind.
Much like the thick fur
that protects
the noble scalewolf.
I never know how hard to push.
[OLRUGGIO] The sad truth is...
people just aren't
as simple as spells.
Speaking of...
Uh? What's this?
Stones?
Snugstones, to be precise.
My latest creation.
They're intended as a sleep aid.
Simply pop one under the covers
and you'll be warmed
from tip to toe.
Might not offer
more than comfort,
but pass them on
to your apprentices.
Thank you, I will.
There's such kindness
in your magic.
Far more than in your words.
Oi! This is purely for research,
you got that?
Before I can start selling
these things,
I need some data
on how effective they are!
We needn't argue
about it, surely.
[QIFREY] Uh?
- Olly...
- [OLRUGGIO] Hm?
You miscounted.
There are five of them.
[OLRUGGIO] Four for the girls.
And one more for you.
That's five.
[Qifrey gasps]
Set a good example for them
and get a good night's sleep.
You are a teacher, eh?
I shall try.
[clattering]
A letter. Who could it be from?
Hello. I've returned.
- [QIFREY] Agott.
- [AGOTT] Uh?
Your timing couldn't be
more convenient.
I've received word
from the Great Hall.
The date for your second test
- has been set.
- [gasps] When do we leave?
- [QIFREY] Three mornings hence.
- [bird screeching]
At Cape Romonon,
in Serpentback Cave.
♪
[RILIPHIN] Are you making
ribbons from crystal?
[RICHEH] Uh?
What a charming spell,
Richehlette.
I'm impressed.
- [Richeh grunts]
- [Riliphin gasps]
[RICHEH] Huh.
Look at it, Rili.
Roly-poly sparkly. Pretty.
[RILIPHIN] Huh.
[Riliphin chuckles softly]
[RICHEH] Huh?
[Richeh sighs]
♪
What is it?
My dear Richeh,
your big brother loves
when you express yourself
through your spells.
Never lose that.
Stay true to who you are.
[RICHEH] Rili?
Where are you going?
Do you not want to look
at my spells anymore?
Don't go.
Rili!
[Richeh groans softly]
A dream.
[Agott groans] How could I have
let myself fall asleep?
I'd resolved to dedicate
every available moment
before the test to practicing!
These blasted Snugstones!
Curse them
and their luxurious warmth!
- [OLRUGGIO] Yeah!
- [all laugh]
[QIFREY] All is well, Agott.
Everyone always worries
they haven't prepared enough.
It's natural.
Approach it as the person
you are now...
In service to the person
you'll be next time.
[Agott inhales]
[AGOTT]
There won't be a next time.
I am of House Arklaum.
I will be passing this test
on my first try.
[MAN] My!
what a heartening pronouncement!
Different as night and day
from this sad little failure.
My apprentice Euini
has failed this test twice,
despite having
only one chance a year.
A remarkable disappointment!
I'd trade the lad away
without a thought
to have an Arklaum daughter
under my wing!
[QIFREY] Master Kukrow...
Apprentices are human beings.
Not possessions to be traded.
[KUKROW] But that would be
preferable, no?
A faulty possession
can be repaired.
How dare you speak like that!
[EUINI] Oh. It's fine, really.
After all, what he says is true.
I am a poor apprentice,
and I've caused Master Kukrow
no end of trouble. So...
I apologize that
my incompetence continues
to reflect so poorly
on you, Master!
And furthermore,
please allow me
to apologize in advance
- for my future incompetence!
- [QIFREY] Are you all right?
[WOMAN] Sorry to have kept
everyone waiting!
As it happens,
the closest Windowway
has become unusable.
I had to walk all the way here.
Quite the imposition!
It's a giant brushbuddy!
And it's talking to me!
[gasps softly]
Hate to disappoint,
but look a bit more closely.
- She's a witch.
- [COCO] What?
Aren't transformation spells
forbidden?
[ALAIRA] A Mirror Cloak
of Borrowshade.
A magical contraption
that handily allows its wearer
to project the illusionary guise
of a nearby beast.
A pleasure to meet you.
I am Alaira.
And it will be my responsibility
to administer
the second test here today.
You'll be
the test proctor, then?
Pure coincidence!
I see you've brought
the apprentices
who aren't testing today
as well.
♪
The second test,
the Sincerity of the Shield.
As the name suggests,
you become like
a protective knight,
ensuring the safety
of your target
as you escort them
through the Serpentback Cave
from its entrance to its exit.
At no time may you
lose sight of your charge.
If either of you reaches
the cave exit alone,
you will have failed.
Furthermore,
being seen casting a spell
will also constitute a failure.
[AGOTT] Does being seen
casting a spell
pose some kind of danger?
[ALAIRA] Well, there's
no risk of exposing
the secrets of magic,
but you will fail nonetheless.
For you'll have exposed
your humanity.
Shall we proceed?
Put on your cloaks
and have a look.
[Coco gasps softly]
- [birds squawking]
- [all gasp excitedly]
[COCO] Are those gryphons?
Close, but no, they're myrphons.
A species that lives
near the water.
The Serpentback Cave,
our test site,
is a ruin from
a more tumultuous age.
A labyrinth spell
pervades its caverns,
making it highly dangerous
to stray from the path.
[squawking]
[AGOTT] So, the object
of the second test
is to use our magic
to protect them from magic?
That's the gist!
It's exceedingly rare for humans
to enter the ruins.
But for ages now, the animals
have been using them
as a route between
their breeding grounds
and their winter nests.
We witches must take
responsibility
for altering their environment.
And so, every year,
when the young ones embark
on that journey
for the first time,
we offer guidance and protection
to keep them from going astray.
As long as you remain
shrouded in those cloaks,
the myrphons will perceive you
as one of their own.
But take care,
for if you should remove them
or disrupt their seal,
the myrphons will flee!
[AGOTT] So that's it.
Compared to drawing spells
without being seen by humans,
this might actually be harder.
[ALAIRA] You'll each be
in charge of a myrphon.
This one is yours,
young man.
- And here's yours.
- [squawking]
And this last one goes...
to you.
[squealing]
Richeh too?
[RICHEH] Sorry,
there's been a mistake.
I'm not taking the test.
That certainly is confusing.
I was sure you applied.
[QIFREY] There's no mistake.
You'll be
taking the test, Richeh.
It's true.
[Richeh gasps]
[wind blowing]
You liar.
Richeh.
I know you remember.
You said you'd always
let me do what I wanted.
That was the reason
I came to you
in the first place.
But in the end, you don't care
what I want, either.
You're just another adult
making rules.
[QIFREY] I care
very much what you want.
That's why I'd like you
to take this test.
Because I care.
I believe that
what you will learn from it
will empower you to live
the life you want to live.
So...
May I ask you for your trust
this one time?
[Richeh sighs]
[Coco gasps]
[RICHEH] I'll take it,
but I'm doing it the way I want.
[QIFREY] Hm.
Hm. Fine with me.
[RICHEH]
If I try it and hate it,
I'll never do it again.
And if it makes me
stop being me,
this will be the last time
I ever trust a word you say!
[running footsteps]
[KUKROW] It appears
you have a handful of your own.
I'm afraid fools like that
have no hope of being corrected.
Nothing but complaints
and excuses from them.
[sighs]
Honestly,
it's all such a bother.
- Why can't children be more--
- [QIFREY] What was that?
Sorry. Could I trouble you
to repeat yourself?
[Kukrow gasps]
Ah, but the hour grows late!
I must be making my way
back to the Great Hall.
[Qifrey gasps]
You mean you're not staying
for your apprentice's test?
[KUKROW] Huh? Surely you two
have the situation well in hand.
Stop dilly-dallying
and get to it!
Incredible! He really left!
Euini.
I'll do my best not to fail,
I promise!
Yes. Good. I suppose.
The time is near.
[QIFREY] May they each
elude the darkness,
and reach the end safely.
For that is why we have magic.
[birds screeching]
The migration has begun.
♪
All right, follow me.
[grunts softly]
♪
[TETIA] Off they go.
Now then, might I interest
the two of you
in a late breakfast?
I could share
a bit of history as well.
History?
[QIFREY] Yes.
You don't know terribly much
about magical ruins
like the Serpentback Cave,
do you?
[Agott panting]
[QIFREY] The effects
of forbidden spells
drawn before
the Day of the Pact...
[Agott gasps]
[QIFREY]...still linger
across the world like scars.
What? This is the road
we have to take.
As you said,
the goal is to use magic
to protect against magic.
And so,
my little magic knights,
show me how
you'll traverse this path.
[♪ closing theme song playing]